Let's take a close look at these red and blue vectors.
我们仔细看看这两个红色和蓝色向量
In fact, let's try looking at them in the original i hat j hat basis.
我们在原始的 i 尖和 j 尖基向量语言中看看它们
In the original basis,
在原始的基向量语言中
the first vector can be written (1,0.5).
第一个向量可以写成 (1,0.5)
That is to say it can be created with one i hat and a half a j hat.
也就是说 可以用 1 个 i 尖和 0.5 个 j 尖表示它
The second vector is (-1,1) so it can be created with minus one i hat and one j hat.
第二个向量是 (-1,1) 所以可以用 -1 个 i 尖和 1 个 j 尖表示它
Here, we've learned how to write the vectors of
我们学会了使用旧的基向量语言
the new basis in the language of the old basis.
表示新的基向量语言中的向量
So, we effectively know how to translate between them.
我们知道如何在这两种基向量语言之间转换
Now, let's see how we can use this information to take a vector expressed
下面看看如何根据这一知识
in one basis and find out how to express it in another basis.
用第二种基向量表示用第一种基向量表示的向量
We know that we need two copies of the blue vector and
我们需要两个蓝色向量
one of the red vector to represent our original vector,
和一个红色向量来表示原始向量
let's write that down.
写下来
When we multiply it out,
相乘后
we see that we recover our vector as written in the i hat,
回到了用 i 尖和 j 尖表示的向量
j hat basis, which makes sense since we know that
这很合理
these vectors are also written in the i hat j hat basis.
因为我们知道这些向量也是用 i 尖和 j 尖基向量表示的
So, now we can see how translation between the two languages works.
现在我们知道在两种语言之间转换的原理了
We need to write the new basis vectors in the language of the old basis,
我们需要用旧的基向量表示新的基向量
then the formula for building the vector in the language of
然后 使用新的基向量语言表示向量的公式
the new basis gives us our vector in the language of the old basis.
就会得出用旧的基向量语言表示的向量
Conversely, if we were starting with (1,2) in our original language of i hat,
相反 如果一开始知道用原始 i 尖和 j 尖表示的 (1,2)
j hat and we wanted to translate to this new basis,
我们想要转换成这个新的基向量语言
we'd have to find out how to write i hat and j hat in the new basis.
那么我们需要知道如何用新的基向量表示 i 尖和 j 尖
Then, we'd multiply it by that matrix
然后与此矩阵相乘
and outward pop our original vector in the new basis.
得出用新的基向量表示的原始向量
It turns out that the matrix that tells you how to translate
实际上 告诉你如何从旧的基向量语言
from the language of the old basis to the language of the new basis
转换成新的基向量语言的矩阵
is just the inverse of the matrix that tells you how to
就是告诉你如何从新的基向量语言
translate from the language of the new basis to the language of the old basis.
转换成旧的基向量语言的矩阵的颠倒形式
This makes sense because translating from the old basis to the new basis and
这很合理 因为在旧的基向量和新的基向量之间来回转换
back should have the effect of doing nothing and give you back what you started with.
应该不会带来任何改变 只是返回一开始的向量
I'll let you verify this for yourself.
请自己验证一遍